Partial Guide to the I. Edward Kiev Papers, circa 1860 - circa 1980 K0001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Pamphlets, circa 1860-circa 1970; K0001 Series 4; 18 linear feet (Box 14, Box 11, Box 16, Box 15, Box 10, Box 51, Box 9, Box 8, Box 7, Box 18, Box 45, Box 46, Box 49, Box 2, Box 1, Box 53, Box 52, Box 48, Box 6, Box 17, Box 5, Box 4, Box 3)
  - Statement to the delegates of the twelfth Zionist Congress: on behalf of the former administration of the Zionist Organization of America, 1921 (Box 49, Folder 1850)
    Also published in Yiddish and German.
  - Arets veha-vodah: kovets le-sifrut ule-nyene ha-vodah veha-yishuv, 08/1918 (Box 49, Folder 1851)
    Organ of ha-Pol ha-tsar Organization, no. 4.
  - Ketuvat pesifas mi-bet hakenesset shel Rehov = Mosaic inscription from the synagogue of Rehov, 1978 (Box 49, Folder 1852)
  - Proceedings of the Pittsburg Rabbinical Conference November 16, 17, 18, 1885, 1923 (Box 49, Folder 1853)
  - Ketoubot d'Afrique du nord a Jerusalem = Ketubot mi-tsfon Afrikah be-Yerushalayim, undated (Box 49, Folder 1854)
    In Hebrew and French
  - Stories about Elijah, 1905 (Box 49, Folder 1855)
  - Saadia al-Fajmi's arabische Psalmenbersetzung, 1880 (Box 49, Folder 1856)
    German and Judeo-Arabic in Arabic script. Inaugural-Dissertation, Kniglichen Universitt Leipzig
  - Pamphlets, undated (Box 51)
  - r ha-pelot, divre sofrim u-medinim l Tel-Aviv le-yovel ha-srim, 1925 (Box 51, Folder 1857)
  - Kuntillet jrud: a religious centre from the time of the Judaean monarchy on the border of Sinai, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 1858)
    Text in English and Hebrew. Exhibition held in honor of Israel's 30th anniversary.
  - Les raisons d'un silence, 1944 (Box 51, Folder 1859)
  - World significance of the Russian revolution, 1921 (Box 51, Folder 1860)
  - Netivot Tsiyon vi-Yerushalayim: ...helek rishon, 1878 (Box 51, Folder 1861)
    Added t.p.: Zion und Jerusalem, ein [sic] Topographie von Jerusalem und seinen Umgebungen samt viel [sic] Ansichten und artischtische [sic] Beilagen.
  - Buch der Gesetze: nach seiner anlage und seinem inhalt untersucht, 1881 (Box 51, Folder 1862)
    Sonderausdruck aus Moses Ben Maimon Bd. I.
  - German-Jewish intellectual influences on American Jewish life, 1842-1972 (Box 51, Folder 1863)
    The B. G. Rudolph lectures in Judaic studies, 1972
  - Are the Jews still the people of the book?, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 1864)
  - Face of the land: 16 photographic studies, 1940 (Box 51, Folder 1865)
    Collection of 16 black and white photographs with captions in English, Spanish, and French
  - Excavations in the Old City of Jerusalem; preliminary report of the first season, 1968, 1969 (Box 51, Folder 1866)
    Translated from an article in Eretz-Israel, volume 9, the W. F. Albright volume
  - Jewish people, a pictorial history, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 1885)
  - Bedeutung der Juden fr Erhaltung und Wiederbelebung der Wissenschaften im Mittelalter, 1877 (Box 51, Folder 1902)
    Book plate: Ex libris Dr. F. M. Warburg
  - Bedeutung der Juden fr Erhaltung und Wiederbelebung der Wissenschaften im Mittelalter, 1922 (Box 51, Folder 1903)
  - Politische Idee des Judentums, 1924 (Box 51, Folder 1904)
  - Megillat Taanit as a source for Jewish chronology and history in the Hellenistic and Roman periods, 1922 (Box 51, Folder 1905)
    Thesis (Ph. D.)--Dropsie College, 1917
  - Erets Yisraoel ben dat u-politikah: ha-tenuh la-tsirat ha-nesigah be-Sinai u-lekaheha = Eretz Israel between politics and religion, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 1906)
    Presented by Samuel Halperin to the I. Edward Kiev Judaica Collection
  - Kavim le-toldot ha-shah, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 1907)
    Gift of Samuel Halperin
  - Hebraica & Judaica including a fine collection of holy land maps and views, Thursday, September 25, 1986 at 10:30 AM, 9/1986 (Box 51, Folder 1908)
  - 15th, 16th & 17th century books, Judaica, Hebraica: b Thursday, February 1, 1979 at 10:30 PM. (Box 51, Folder 1909)
  - Hebraica & Judaica: public auction sale 1612, Thursday, December 17, 1992 at 10:30 A.M., 12/17/1992 (Box 51, Folder 1910)
  - Hebraica & Judaica: public auction sale 1580: Thursday, December 19, 1991 at 1:00 pm., 12/19/1991 (Box 51, Folder 1911)
  - Hebraica & Judaica including group of books illustrated by El Lissitzky..., Sunday, June 24, 1990 at 10:00 AM. and 1:00 PM., 6/20/1990 (Box 51, Folder 1912)
  - Hebraica & Judaica: public auction sale 1645, Thursday, December 16, 1993 at 10:30 A.M, 12/16/1993 (Box 51, Folder 1913)
  - Hebraica & Judaica: including duplicates from the library of Professor Salo W. Baron at Stanford University, 1991 (Box 51, Folder 1914)
  - Hebraica & Judaica: public auction sale 1630: Thursday, June 24, 1993 at 10:30 a.m., 6/24/1993 (Box 51, Folder 1915)
  - Hebraica & Judaica: public auction sale 1598, Thursday, June 25, 1992 at 10:30 A.M., 6/25/1992 (Box 51, Folder 1916)
  - Hebraica & Judaica: public auction sale 1565: Tuesday, June 25, 1991 at 1:00 pm., 6/25/1991 (Box 51, Folder 1917)
  - Jewish history and literature; a course of lessons from the rise of the Kabbala to the expulsion of the Jews by Spain, 1899 (Box 51, Folder 1919)
    Chautauqua system of education. Department of Jewish studies. Course book, pt. 4
  - Historical sketch of the Jews since the destruction of Jerusalem, 1887 (Box 51, Folder 1920)
  - Geschichte der Juden seit dem Untergang des jdischen Staates, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 1921)
    Aus Natur und Geisteswelt
  - Hebraica & Judaica comprising: American Judaica..., Thursday, April 30, 1987 at 7:00 PM., 4/30/1987 (Box 51, Folder 1922)
  - Hebraica & Judaica including an extensive collection of early printed books, Sunday, December 17, 1989 at 10:00 AM., 12/17/1989 (Box 51, Folder 1923)
  - Hebraica & Judaica: Thursday, June 28, 1984 at 1:30 PM., 6/24/1984 (Box 51, Folder 1924)
  - Catalogue of fine Judaica books, manuscripts and works of art: b the property of various owners including the late Rabbi Dr. Leonard C. Mishkin, Chicago: property from the collection of Molly Picon, sold by order of the present owner, property sold to benefit The Jewish Museum, New York, Fine Arts Acquisition Fund, 3/3/1998 (Box 51, Folder 1925)
    English and Hebrew.
  - Fine Judaica: books, manuscripts and works of art, 11/24/1982 (Box 51, Folder 1926)
  - Fine Judaica and related works of art: property of various owners ...: exhibition, Nov. 19-24, 1981 ...: public auction, Nov. 25, 1981, 11/25/1981 (Box 51, Folder 1927)
  - Fine Printed & Manuscript Judaica, 5/11/1981 (Box 51, Folder 1928)
  - Highly important Judaica: Sotheby's, New York galleries, Thursday, June 23, 1983., 6/23/1983 (Box 51, Folder 1929)
  - Important Judaica: works of art: auction, Wednesday, June 27, at 1984 at 2 p.m., 6/27/1984 (Box 51, Folder 1930)
  - Important Hebrew printed books and manuscripts: Tuesday, December 4, 1984, at 3:00 p.m., 12/4/1984 (Box 51, Folder 1931)
  - Important Hebraica: Hebrew printed books and manuscripts: auction, Wednesday, February 1, 1984, at 2 p.m., 2/1/1984 (Box 51, Folder 1932)
  - German jewry: its history and culture: Catalogue; no. 39, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 1933)
  - Hebrew books and works of art, 2/4/1988 (Box 51, Folder 1934)
  - Antique Judaica: books, maps, Jewish art, ritual silver & ceremonial Judaica, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 1935)
    Gift of Samuel Halperin.
  - Antique Judaica: books, maps, Jewish art, ritual silver & ceremonial Judaica, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 1936)
  - Hebraica-Judaica: Antiquariaat Pampiere Wereld, Amsterdam, 3/22/1992 (Box 51, Folder 1937)
  - Judaic books, manuscripts and works of art: the property of various owners ... December 6 and 7, 1984, 12/6/1984 - 12/7/1984 (Box 51, Folder 1938)
  - Important Judaica: books, manuscripts and works of art, 11/25/1985 (Box 51, Folder 1939)
  - Auction of important & rare Judaica, books, manuscripts and works of art, 6/16/1999 (Box 51, Folder 1940)
    Yeshiva Ahavas Torah Baranovich-Jerusalem presents an auction of important & rare Judaica, books, manuscripts and works of art
  - Yudaikah Yerushalem: tetsugah u-mekhirah pumbit bi-Yerushalayim shel sefarim Ivriyim atikim, teudot historiyot, kitve yad nedirim ve-omanut Yehudit = Judaica Jerusalem, 4/14/1996 (Box 51, Folder 1941)
  - Tetsugah u-mekhirah pumbit bi-Yerushala[y]im: shel sefarim Ivriyim atikim, teudot historiyot, kitve yad nedirim ve-omanut Yehudit ... 20 Adar 759, 8 be-Merts 1999 ..., 3/8/1999 (Box 51, Folder 1942)
    The auction will take place on Monday, 8th of March, 1999 at 5:30 p.m. at the Laromme Jerusalem Hotel. The exhibition and display of items will be held at the Exhibition Halls of the Society ...
  - Yudaikah Yerushalem: tetsugah u-mekhirah pumbit bi-Yerushalayim shel sefarim Ivriyim atikim, teudot historiyot, kitve yad nedirim ve-omanut Yehudit = Judaica Jerusalem, 11/11/1996 (Box 51, Folder 1943)
  - Yudaikah Yerushalem: tetsugah u-mekhirah pumbit bi-Yerushalayim shel sefarim Ivriyim atikim, teudot historiyot, kitve yad nedirim ve-omanut Yehudit = Judaica Jerusalem, 10/25/1995 (Box 51, Folder 1944)
  - Yudaikah Yerushalem: tetsugah u-mekhirah pumbit bi-Yerushalayim shel sefarim vriyim tikim, tudot historiyot, kitve yad nedirim ve-omanut Yehudit = Judaica Jerusalem, 11/11/1996 (Box 51, Folder 1945)
  - Yudaikah Yerushalem: tetsugah u-mekhirah pumbit bi-Yerushalayim shel sefarim vriyim tikim, tudot historiyot, kitve yad nedirim ve-omanut Yehudit = Judaica Jerusalem, 6/8/1999 (Box 51, Folder 1946)
  - Yudaikah Yerushalem: tetsugah u-mekhirah pumbit bi-Yerushalayim shel sefarim vriyim tikim, tudot historiyot, kitve yad nedirim ve-omanut Yehudit = Judaica Jerusalem, 8/31/1990 (Box 51, Folder 1947)
    The Sheer Yashuv catalogue No. 1
  - Fine Judaica, books and works of art: [auction], 5:30 pm Thursday May 9th 1996, 406 East 79th Street, New York, 5/9/1996 (Box 51, Folder 1948)
    sale no. 747
  - Fine Judaica, Hebrew books and works of art: 5:30 pm, November 26th 1996 ... New York, 11/26/1996 (Box 51, Folder 1949)
  - Further ninety-seven highly important Hebrew manuscripts: from the collection formed by the late David Solomon Sassoon, the property of the family of David Solomon Sassoon, 12/4/1984 (Box 51, Folder 1950)
  - Pamphlets, undated (Box 52)
  - Judaica: books, manuscripts and works of art, 5/5/1988 (Box 52, Folder 1951)
  - Important Judaica: b including a highly important and exceptionally rare painted wooden sukkah, circa 1800 and a unique Judaeo-Arabic Astrolabe, probably circa 1300: sale Thursday 15 December 1988 at 10.30 a.m., 12/15/1988 (Box 52, Folder 1952)
  - Important judaica, 4/24/1997 (Box 52, Folder 1953)
  - Important Judaica: books, manuscripts and works of art, 10/2/1991 (Box 52, Folder 1954)
  - Important Judaica: Friday, 12th April 1996 at 10:30 a.m., 4/12/1996 (Box 52, Folder 1955)
    "This catalogue may be referred to as IS9602 'Passover'."
  - Important Hebrew manuscripts and printed books ... Christie's, Wednesday, June 23, 1999, 10 am, 6/23/1996 (Box 52, Folder 1956)
  - Fine Judaica: including a highly important collection of circa 420 manuscript documents relating to the Jewish communities of the Dutch West Indies ..., 5/11/1988 (Box 52, Folder 1957)
  - Fine Judaica: including a highly important mediaeval illuminated Hebrew manuscript, 6/21/1989 (Box 52, Folder 1958)
  - A.L. Shane Collection of Judaica and Hebraica: auction: Wednesday, 24, June 1998 ..., 6/24/1998 (Box 52, Folder 1959)
  - Catalogue of fine Judaica books, manuscripts and works of art including a distinguished European collection of early printed Hebrew books and the property of the late Leyzer Ran, New York: to be offered for sale by auction on Thursday, November 14, 1996 at 6:00 pm precisely, 11/14/1996 (Box 52, Folder 1960)
  - Catalogue of fine Judaica books, manuscripts and works of art including a Dutch private collector and the property of the Late T. Nachum Gidal, Jerusalem: to be offered for sale by auction on Tuesday, June 3, 1997 at 4:00 pm precisely, 6/3/1997 (Box 52, Folder 1961)
  - Fine Judaica: books, manuscripts and works of art, 6/23/1998 (Box 52, Folder 1962)
  - Catalogue of fine Hebrew printed books: duplicates from the Library of the Jewish Theological Seminary of America including a selection of Old-Yiddish printed books: with a collection of Anglo-Judaica, the property of a gentleman, property from the collection of the late David Frankel, Husiatyn-Vienna-New York, sold by order of the present owner, the property of a private collector, New York, 11/25/1997 (Box 52, Folder 1963)
  - Important Hebrew and Samaritan manuscripts from the collection formed by the late David Solomon Sassoon: exhibition, London, Apr. 14-16, 1981; New York, May 6-8, 1981: public auction, May 12, 1981, 5/12/1981 (Box 52, Folder 1964)
  - Catalogue of thirty-three highly important Hebrew and Samaritan manuscripts from the collection formed by the Late David Solomon Sassoon ... which will be sold at auction, 11/21/1978 (Box 52, Folder 1965)
  - Catalogue of fine Judaica: early printed & illustrated books, manuscripts and works of graphic art: including a fine selection of photography and posters., 1/27/2004 (Box 52, Folder 1966)
    Fine Judaica: early printed & illustrated books, manuscripts and works of graphic art
  - Fine Judaica: Hebrew printed books, manuscripts & ceremonial art ..., 6/29/2004 (Box 52, Folder 1967)
  - Catalogue of fine Judaica books, manuscripts and works of art: b the property of various owners including the late Bernard & Francis Lustig Collection of Judaica: the property of H.E. Prince Nicolai Callimachi of Moldovia: a large collection of Hagadoth - the property of a gentleman., 6/22/1999 (Box 52, Folder 1968)
  - Kefar be-rosh-ha-har, 1967 (Box 52, Folder 1969)
  - Be-tsumam shel keravot, 1967 (Box 52, Folder 1970)
  - Bayit ha-boded, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 1971)
  - Unsung heroes: a collection of tales of Haganah, 1948 (Box 52, Folder 1972)
    Collection of materials of the Kibbutz Hameuchad and the Hebrew press, particulary the journal, Bamaaleh, and the daily newspaper, Davar
  - Hagadah le-Yom ha-atsmaut, 1968 (Box 52, Folder 1973)
  - Tsiyunim le-shevah ahare maarekhet Sinai, 1968 (Box 52, Folder 1974)
  - Yom ha-zikaron ha-kelali le-halele Tsahal, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 1975)
  - Din ve-heshbon: la-moshav ha-asiri shel asefat ha-nivharim, Adar 702-Merts 1942 (Box 52, Folder 1976)
  - Araberfrage in Palstina: Sammelbuch, 1921 (Box 52, Folder 1977)
  - Ha-kerav nimshakh be-ulam bet ha-din: mishpat ha-sheloshim ve-ehad hayale ha-Irgun ha-Tsevai ha-Leumi bifne bet din ha-Tsevai ha-Briti ba-Yerushalayim, Sivan 706, 1947 (Box 52, Folder 1978)
  - Chaim Weizman: excerpts from his historic statements, writings and addresses, a biography with an introduction by Dr. Nahum Goldman, 1952 (Box 52, Folder 1979)
  - JNF handbook: Chaim Weizmann Issue, 1963 (Box 52, Folder 1980)
  - Tsiyonut: Me'ah shenot ha-rishonut, 1997 (Box 52, Folder 1982)
  - Bibliyografyah mi-tokh R. de Vaux Ancient Israel, 1961, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 1983)
  - Mabua; devoted to Hebrew literature, scholarship and thought: no. 4, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 1984)
  - Antisemitizm un Yidisher natsionalizm, 1929 (Box 52, Folder 1985)
  - Israel and the Jews in the Soviet mirror: Soviet cartoons on the Middle East crisis, 1967 (Box 52, Folder 1986)
  - Fashizm un antisemitizm in Amerike, 1934 (Box 52, Folder 1987)
  - Vegn dem moralishe anblik fun undzer folk, 1945 (Box 52, Folder 1988)
    O moral'nom oblike nashego naroda. Yiddish
  - Rezolutsie funem politishn biuro funem Ts. K. fun der Rumenisher Arbeter-Partey in der natsionaler frage, 1948 (Box 52, Folder 1989)
    Rezolutia Biroului Politic al C.C. al Partidului Muncitoresc Roma^n in chestiunea nationala
  - Vegn religye, 1930 (Box 52, Folder 1990)
    Translation of O religii. Yiddish
  - Viazoy lebn Yidn in Sovetnland, 1940 (Box 52, Folder 1991)
    Cover title: Zhizn' evreev v strane sovetov
  - Birobidzshanboy, 1932 (Box 52, Folder 1992)
    Title on added title page: Birobidzhanstroi
  - Vos darf visn an ibervanderer vegn der Yidisher avtonomer gegnt?, 1939 (Box 52, Folder 1993)
    Chto dolzhen znat' pereselenets o Evreiskoi avtonomnoi oblasti
  - Yidishe froyen: fartseykhenungen, 1943 (Box 52, Folder 1994)
  - Literatur-frages ba Marksn un Engelsn: etyudn, 1934 (Box 52, Folder 1995)
  - Folkslider vegn der foterlendisher milkhome, 1944 (Box 52, Folder 1996)
    Title on p. [4] of cover: Narodnye pesni ob otechestvennoi voine
  - Dape ezer la-martseh: hov. 70 (April 1966): "Poshe ha-Natsim veha-din, 4/1966 (Box 52, Folder 1997)
  - Oswiecim, camp of death: (underground report), 1944 (Box 52, Folder 1998)
    At head of title: Underground Poland speaks
  - British projects for the restoration of the Jews, 1917 (Box 52, Folder 19999)
    The British Palestine committee. Publications. no. 1
  - Jdische Geschichte: Ein geschichtsphilosophischer Versuch. Autorisierte bersetzung aus dem Russischen von Israel Friedlnder, 1921 (Box 52, Folder 2000)
    2. Aufl.
  - Quinque volumina: Canticum Canticorum. Ruth. Threni. Ecclesiastes. Esther. Textum Masoreticum accuratissime expressit, e fontibus Masorae varie illustravit, notis criticis confirmavit, 1886 (Box 52, Folder 2001)
    At head of title: Hamesh Megilot: Shir ha-shirim; Rut; Kinot; Kohelet; Ester
  - Pamphlets, undated (Box 53)
  - Rom und Jerusalem: die letzte Nationalittsfrage: Briefe, 1919 (Box 53, Folder 2002)
    Jdische Handbcher; 3-5
  - Maarekhet ha-bitahon u-terumatah la-kidmah ha-tekhnologit, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 2003)
    Pirsume hartsaot Mosad Van Lir bi-Yerushalayim; 6. Title on verso t.p.: The defense establishment and its contribution to technological progress
  - Tikhnun lumi be-Yisrel--tsorekh ve-efsharut: diyun, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 2004)
    Title on verso t.p.: National planning in Israel--need and possibility
  - Sefer Yosifon in idish, 1961 (Box 53, Folder 2005)
    Attributed erroneously to Joseph ben Gorion, ha-Kohen
  - Perush Mishle: meyuhas bi-khetav-yad Oksford le-R. Avraham Ibn zra; hotso le-r Shemuel Rols Driver = A commentary on the book of Proverbs attributed to Abraham ibn Ezra., 1880 (Box 53, Folder 2006)
    Introduction in English, text is in Hebrew. Includes added Hebrew t.p.
  - Stone which the modern builders rejected, 1960 (Box 53, Folder 2007)
    The Goldenson lecture for 1960
  - Writings Of Osias Heschel Schorr; a Bibliography; Studies in Bibliography and Booklore, vol. 2 no. 1, 6/1955 (Box 53, Folder 2008)
    Autographed by author on cover, inscribed "To Kiev - gratefully E. Spicehandler"
  - Prohibitions against loans at interest in ancient Hebrew laws: off-print from Hebrew Union College Annual; vol. 26, 1955 (Box 53, Folder 2009)
    Autographed by author on cover, inscribed "To Rabbi I. Edward Kiev with the authors warmest regards."
  - R. Isaac B. Yeda`ya: a forgotten commentator on the ggada, 1/1979 - 6/1979 (Box 53, Folder 2010)
    off print from Revue des tudes juives: tome CXXXVIII; janvier-junin 1979; fascicule 1-2
  - Exile in Amsterdam: the evidence in the sermons of Saul Levi Morteira, 2001 (Box 53, Folder 2011)
    offprint from Me'ah sherim: yunim be-lamam ha-ruhani shel Yisra'el bi-Yeme ha-Benayim: le-zekher Yitshak Tverski
  - Earliest commentary on the Midrash Rabbah, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 2012)
    offprint from Studies in Medieval Jewish Jistory and Literature
  - Selected passages from Yedaiah Bedersi's commentary on the Midrashim, 1984 (Box 53, Folder 2013)
  - Inscribed for life or death?, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 2014)
    offprint from the Journal of Reform Judaism
  - Preaching for Pesach, 1987 (Box 53, Folder 2015)
    offprint from The Journal of Reform Judaism
  - Book Review: Shir ha-Malot l'David (Song of the Steps) and Ktav hitnazzelut l'Darshanim (In Defense of Preachers) & A Guide for Preachers on Composing and Delivering Sermons: The Or ha-Darshanim of Jacob Zahalon, 1987 (Box 53, Folder 2016)
    offprint from Thew Journal of Reform Judaism
  - Book Reviews: The world of a Renaissance Jew: The Life and Thought of Abraham ben Mordecai Farissol, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 2017)
  - Reviews: Nehemia Polen: The Holy Fire: the Teachings of Rabbi Kalonymus Shapira, the Rebbe of the Warsaw Ghetto, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 2018)
    offprint from Modern Judaism 16
  - Recent Publications in the Jewish-Christian Dialogue: A Review Essay, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 2019)
    offprint of Modern Judaism: vol. 2
  - Jewish-Christian Relations in the Middle Ages: Misconceptions, realities, enigmas, 1993 (Box 53, Folder 2020)
    offprint from The CCAR Journal: A Reform Jewish Quarterly
  - Christians and Jews - Some Positive Images, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 2021)
    offprint from The Harvard theological review, vol. 79: no.1-3
  - Notes: HaLevi's west wind, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 2022)
    offprint from Prooftyexts; vol. 1
  - Review Essay: Jewish Preachers and their Literary Remains; Ella Almagor; Kitvei ha-Yad shel Midreshei R. David ha-Nagid - Shaul Regev (editor) Derashot R. Yishaq Karo, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 2023)
    offprint from The Jewish Quartetrly Review, LXXXVII, nos.1-2
  - Medieval Jewish Sermon, 2000 (Box 53, Folder 2024)
    offprint from Typologie des Sources du Moyen ge Occidental: Fasc. 81-83
  - Preaching of repentance and the reforms in Toledo of 1281, 1990 - 2000 (Box 53, Folder 2025)
  - Book Reviews: Carmi Horowitz - The Jewish Sermon in 14th Century Spain: the Derashot of R. Joshua ibn Shu'eib., 1990 - 2000 (Box 53, Folder 2026)
  - Isaac Abrabanel's stance towrad tradition: defense, dissent, and dialogue: by Eric Lawee, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 2027)
    Offprint from Hebrew Studies vol. XLIII, 2002
  - Saul Levi Morteira's Treatise on the immortality of the soul, 1991 (Box 53, Folder 2028)
    Offprint from Studia Rosenthaliana: vol. 25, no 2: Fall 1991
  - History as homiletics: the use of historical memory in the sermons of Saul Levi Morteira, 1998 (Box 53, Folder 2029)
    offprint from Jewish history and Jewish memory: essays in honor of Yosef Hayim Yerushalmi
  - Polish Jewry: Open or Closed?, 1990 (Box 53, Folder 2030)
    Offprint from Prooftexts
  - Book Review: A "Ritual Dance of Destruction"? The Jewish Messiahs: from Galilee to Crown Heights by Harris Lenowitz, 1999 (Box 53, Folder 2031)
    offprint from Jewish Quarterly Review vol. XC nos.1-2
  - Jewish Typological Exegesis after Nahmanides, 1993 - 1994 (Box 53, Folder 2032)
    offprint from Jewish Studies Quarterly vol. 1, no. 2 (1993/94)
  - Conflict over the Rashba's herem on philosophical study: a political perspective, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 2033)
    offprint from Jewish history: vol. 1 no. 2
  - Martyrs, mercants and rabbis: Jewish communal as reflected in the responsa on the boycott of Ancona, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 2034)
    offprint from Jewish Social Studies: vol. XLIII, nos. 3-4
  - Yedaiah Bedersi's commentary on the Midrashim, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 2035)
    offprint from Proceedings of the Eight World Congress of Jewish Studies, division C Talmud and Midrash, Philosophy and Mysticism Hebrew and Yiddish Literature
  - Stories in Jewish Sermons (the 15th-16th centuries), 1986 (Box 53, Folder 2036)
    off print from Ninth World Congress of Jewish Studies, division C Talmud and Midrash, Philosophy and Mysticism Hebrew and Yiddish Literature
  - Center for the Study of World Religions: Bulletin, 1985 (Box 53, Folder 2037)
  - Derashot mi-Byzantium be-ktav yad, 1993 (Box 53, Folder 2038)
    offprint from Pe'amim: Studies in Oriental Jewry, 78
  - Darshah ki-edut le-hepatsat rayonot filosofayim be-mah 15, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 2039)
    offprint from ha-Tarbut ha-mamit: kovets mehkarim
  - Worship (First draft), 3/15/1959 (Box 53, Folder 2040)
    Prepared for presentation to the Conference on Worship Research of the Union of American Hebrew Congregations
  - Vietnam's challenge to conscience -- and the Jewish tradition, 3/10/1968 (Box 53, Folder 2041)